<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title/><link>https://flatrick.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://flatrick.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Atomic Note</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Atomic-Note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Atomic-Note/</guid><description>Atomic Note An Atomic Note is a note on a single thought/idea.
Consider these points when making a note:
Why is it important to me? Is it inspiring? Can I make use of the information? Is it hard to find the particular piece of information? Was it hard earnt information/knowledge? What is this related to? Should I link to/from the related notes? Should I use a particular tag to group this note with similiar notes?</description></item><item><title>Forgetting Curve</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Forgetting-Curve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Forgetting-Curve/</guid><description>The &amp;ldquo;Forgetting Curve&amp;rdquo; is a theory by Hermann Ebbinghaus produced during his studies on our ability to learn. Here is a simple explanation of his findings:
He first repeatedly read a random list of 3 letter symbols (for example ABC, BAC and so on) until he could recite them correctly (with no mistakes) 20 minutes later, he could correctly recite about 55% of the list 40 minutes after that, he could correctly recite about 45% After 9 hours, it was down to 40% After 24 hours, it was closer to 35% And after 48 hours, it was closer to 30% See figure below for a graphical representation of how much he could remember correctly</description></item><item><title>Leitner system</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Leitner-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Leitner-system/</guid><description>The Leitner System is a methodology for Spaced repetition Flashcards are sorted into groups according to how well the learner knows each one in the Leitner&amp;rsquo;s learning box(es) The student try to recall the solution written on a flashcard If they succeed, they send the card to the next group If they fail, they send it back to the first group An alternative is to only move the card into the box in the preceeding level (i.</description></item><item><title>List of Topics</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/moc/List-of-Topics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/moc/List-of-Topics/</guid><description>This page serves as a central point to all my &amp;ldquo;maps&amp;rdquo; of various topics.
Studying Note taking Habits-and-Willpower</description></item><item><title>Note taking</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/moc/Note-taking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/moc/Note-taking/</guid><description> Atomic Note Cataloging-and-Classification ]</description></item><item><title>Overlearning</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Overlearning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Overlearning/</guid><description>Overlearning is when a student repeats the study of the material more times than is necessary to perfectly repeat the content from memory, as defined by Hermann Ebbinghaus.
Based on later findings in the 1900s and later, it is clear that overlearning only has any benefits for short-term memory retention. For long-term retention, Spaced repetition is one of the most efficient methods available, if not the most efficient one. Combined with the knowledge of the Forgetting Curve , it is easy to see how Spaced repetition can be an efficient method for long-term memory retention.</description></item><item><title>SQxR</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/SQxR/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/SQxR/</guid><description>SQxR refers to the two acronyms [[SQxR#SQ3R]] and [[SQxR#SQ4R]] which are names of two related study methodologies.
SQ3R stands for Survey, Question, Read, Retrieve &amp;amp; Review SQ4R stands for Survey, Question, Read, Recite, Relate &amp;amp; Review SQ3R Survey (&amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo;) The first step, survey or skim, advises that one should resist the temptation to read the book and instead first go through a chapter and note the headings, sub-headings and other outstanding features, such as figures, tables, and summary paragraphs.</description></item><item><title>Studying</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/moc/Studying/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/moc/Studying/</guid><description> Forgetting-Curve Leitner-system Overlearning Spaced-repetition SQxR</description></item></channel></rss>