<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://flatrick.github.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2 minute rule</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/2-minute-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/2-minute-rule/</guid><description> &amp;ldquo;If something can be done in two minutes, do it immediately&amp;rdquo;
The idea is to get the momentum going and getting those quick and easy things done as soon as possible. Every time we finish a task, the brain will create a dose of dopamine making us feel better, and that will in turn make our brain create a craving for another dose of dopamine.
Sources # How the 2-minute rule can help you beat procrastination and start new habits Related 5-second-rule 5-minute-rule</description></item><item><title>40 percent rule</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/40-percent-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/40-percent-rule/</guid><description>The first day living with the SEAL, he asked Itzler to jump up on the pull-up bar and do as many pull-ups as he could. Itzler completed 8. He then asked him to jump back up and do it again. This time it was 6. He asked him to jump up a third time, and Itzler squeaked out just a few. The SEAL then told him they weren’t leaving until Itzler completed 100 more.</description></item><item><title>5 minute rule</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/5-minute-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/5-minute-rule/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Promise yourself to do only 5 minutes of work on a task you&amp;rsquo;re putting off&amp;rdquo;
Sometimes, it can be really hard to get started because the task we&amp;rsquo;re going to do just feels overwhelmingly large or complex. Try to break the task down to the smallest possible sub-task (convert it into an Input Based Goal) and give yourself 5 minutes to work on it.
Example: if your goal is to get to the gym, promise yourself that you&amp;rsquo;ll only spend 5 minutes packing your gym-bag.</description></item><item><title>5-second-rule</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/5-second-rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/5-second-rule/</guid><description>When the alarm is going off in the morning, count backwards from 5 and then just sit up. That first unwanted action that we make ourselves do, will make the next difficult (unattractive) choice easier. The more difficult choices we get through, the easier the next ones will be.
If we spend time thinking about doing something for more than 5 seconds without action, our minds are highly likely to begin convincing us to not do it.</description></item><item><title>Atomic Note</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Atomic-Note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Atomic-Note/</guid><description>An Atomic Note is a note on a single thought/idea.
Consider these points when making a note:
Why is it important to me? Is it inspiring? Can I make use of the information? Is it hard to find the particular piece of information? Was it hard earnt information/knowledge? What is this related to? Should I link to/from the related notes? Should I use a particular tag to group this note with similiar notes?</description></item><item><title>Cataloging &amp; Classification</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Cataloging-and-Classification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Cataloging-and-Classification/</guid><description>Tagging is very useful, but the lack of control and meaning breaks things down fast A controlled term is worth a thousand tags Classification is where things go; either on a shelf or in a computer system and so on Cataloging is what we call things; the subject headings, aliases or tags Sources Cataloging, Classification, Information Science, PKMs and YOU! - Obsidian.md Forum Merging library &amp;amp; information science and PKM - How Bri Watson uses Obsidian Related [[Johnny.</description></item><item><title>Eat the frog</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Eat-the-frog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Eat-the-frog/</guid><description>The term &amp;ldquo;Eat the frog&amp;rdquo; refers to the act of just doing that thing we are currently delaying. Often, we&amp;rsquo;re overestimating for example the difficulty or unpleasantness the act of performing a task will cause us, which then causes us to refrain from even starting the task. But by just doing the task as soon as possible, it
“If it&amp;rsquo;s your job to eat a frog, it&amp;rsquo;s best to do it first thing in the morning.</description></item><item><title>Forgetting Curve</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Forgetting-Curve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Forgetting-Curve/</guid><description>The &amp;ldquo;Forgetting Curve&amp;rdquo; is a theory by Hermann Ebbinghaus produced during his studies on our ability to learn. Here is a simple explanation of his findings:
He first repeatedly read a random list of 3 letter symbols (for example ABC, BAC and so on) until he could recite them correctly (with no mistakes) 20 minutes later, he could correctly recite about 55% of the list 40 minutes after that, he could correctly recite about 45% After 9 hours, it was down to 40% After 24 hours, it was closer to 35% And after 48 hours, it was closer to 30% See figure below for a graphical representation of how much he could remember correctly</description></item><item><title>Habit Substitution</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Habit-Substitution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Habit-Substitution/</guid><description> In many cases, it can be more effective to replace your bad habit than to merely try to eliminate it. The beautiful thing about habit substitution is that you can build a good habit and break a bad one at the same time.
Sources - 30 One-Sentence Stories From People Who Have Built Better Habits Related Atomic-Habits The-Three-R_s-of-Habit-Change</description></item><item><title>Leitner system</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Leitner-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Leitner-system/</guid><description>The Leitner System is a methodology for Spaced repetition Flashcards are sorted into groups according to how well the learner knows each one in the Leitner&amp;rsquo;s learning box(es) The student try to recall the solution written on a flashcard If they succeed, they send the card to the next group If they fail, they send it back to the first group An alternative is to only move the card into the box in the preceeding level (i.</description></item><item><title>Overlearning</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Overlearning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Overlearning/</guid><description>Overlearning is when a student repeats the study of the material more times than is necessary to perfectly repeat the content from memory, as defined by Hermann Ebbinghaus.
Based on later findings in the 1900s and later, it is clear that overlearning only has any benefits for short-term memory retention. For long-term retention, Spaced repetition is one of the most efficient methods available, if not the most efficient one. Combined with the knowledge of the Forgetting Curve , it is easy to see how Spaced repetition can be an efficient method for long-term memory retention.</description></item><item><title>Premack's principle</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Premack_s-principle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Premack_s-principle/</guid><description> &amp;ldquo;More probable behaviours will reinforce less probable behaviours.&amp;rdquo;
You become conditioned to do something you don&amp;rsquo;t want to do, because you get to do something else that you want to do when you do the less desirable action.
Sources How to become 37.78 times better at anything | Atomic Habits summary (by James Clear) Related Atomic Habits</description></item><item><title>Smart Notes</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Smart-Notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/Smart-Notes/</guid><description>Creator/Author: Sönke Ahrens
Writing is The Only Thing that Matters: Thinking through the medium of writing will improve your reading, thinking, and other intellectual skills. And so this principle implies you must consume information with the purpose of writing about it. Simplicity is Paramount: To be successful, the system must reduce the number of decisions made by standardized note-taking, having a clear separation between the different types of notes, and designated storage for each type.</description></item><item><title>SQxR</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/SQxR/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/SQxR/</guid><description>SQxR refers to the two acronyms [[SQxR#SQ3R]] and [[SQxR#SQ4R]] which are names of two related study methodologies.
SQ3R stands for Survey, Question, Read, Retrieve &amp;amp; Review SQ4R stands for Survey, Question, Read, Recite, Relate &amp;amp; Review SQ3R Survey (&amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo;) The first step, survey or skim, advises that one should resist the temptation to read the book and instead first go through a chapter and note the headings, sub-headings and other outstanding features, such as figures, tables, and summary paragraphs.</description></item><item><title>The Three R's of Habit Change</title><link>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/The-Three-R_s-of-Habit-Change/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flatrick.github.io/notes/The-Three-R_s-of-Habit-Change/</guid><description> Reminder (the cue that triggers the habit) Routine (the action/habit itself) Reward (the benefit from doing the action/habit) By planning our habit change with these three guidelines, we&amp;rsquo;ll increase our own brain&amp;rsquo;s desire to do what we want and thereby making it a lot easier to stick to a new habit.
Sources The Habits Guide: How to Build Good Habits and Break Bad Ones Related Habit-Substitution</description></item></channel></rss>